Somebody told me once
I fought like I was
trying to destroy
everyone who'd ever
done me wrong.
They said I fought like
I had demons in me.
Maybe it's true.
Maybe I do.
First time I ever
stepped in a boxing ring though,
all I knew was I had to beat
the shit out of that bitch
before she had a chance
to hit me.
Hi!
Hey Momma!
Something's up.
They're being weird.
Check this out.
You won?
- No way.
- Mm-hm.
- Did you get hit?
- Hardly.
I don't know, my eyes were
closed half the time.
Easiest three hundred bucks
I ever made.
- I can't believe you did that.
- I know, me neither.
Three hundred bucks?
Jesus Christ--
Randy Salters!
Language.
Sis won the
Toughman competition.
Check this out.
What's going on?
Why is nobody talking?
Dad!
We'll talk about it after lunch.
What's going on?
Why can't you just--
Pam Doolan called me.
About what?
I don't know.
Maybe she's
confused or something.
But she said some
horrible, horrible things,
about you and that girl.
You know her name's Rosie.
Oh, I don't know what
I know anymore,
because you tell us
she's your team mate,
and then she's
your best friend,
and now Pam is saying
this about you two.
Now Pam is taking her
to see a priest
to get her straightened out,
and Dad and I think that
we should probably do
the same with you.
I'm not going to
see a priest.
Well, Dad and I
have discussed it
and we can't be helping you
with your rent anymore
if you're going to
keep doing this.
Keep doing what?
What the hell
is a priest going to do?
- Is it true?
- Is what true?
- What people are saying.
- What are they saying?
Well, we don't want you
to see her no more.
People are gonna say it's my
fault in the way I raised you.
Who cares what they say?
Pam Doolan is a crazy bitch.
Why the fuck do you care
what she thinks?
Don't you speak
to me like that--
Why the hell not?
You're allowed to say
whatever dumb shit
- pops into your head.
- Stop this!
Just stop!
What you're doing
isn't normal.
And we want you to have
a happy, normal life.
I'm just gonna
go talk to the priest.
I have to do it.
If I don't at least talk to him,
she's gonna cut off
my allowance.
- Just get a job.
- What job?
She's gonna stop paying
for my apartment.
Her cousin has a room.
She wants me
to move in there.
What for?
To keep an eye on me.
Why do you think?
I can't stay.
I gotta go.
Over here!
I got her!
Fucking lesbian.
Break it up now!
Basketball
is a team sport.
You can't be on the team
if you keep punching the
team in the face.
It's not funny.
She started it.
Oh come on, Christy.
Grow up.
Well, she fucking did.
How?
What did she do?
Huh?
What'd she do?
Fuck it. Just forget about it.
It doesn't matter.
Alright, hold your horses,
Casey.
I got you some right here.
Here you go.
You're a madman.
Oh, shit.
Hello, Christy speaking.
Christy,
this is Richard Christmas.
I work for Larry Carrier.
He asked me to call you.
- Sorry, Larry who?
- Larry Carrier.
He's a boxing promoter out
here in Bristol, Tennessee.
Larry saw you fight a few weeks
ago at the Toughman contest.
He owns the
Bristol Speedway
and he's putting
a show together.
He wants to know
how you'd feel about
making your
professional boxing debut.
I'm not... I play basketball.
I'm not a boxer, sir.
I've never been in a
boxing gym in my life.
I entered Toughman for fun.
Well, Larry liked
the way you fought.
We'll put you up in a
nice hotel for the night,
and the purse is
five hundred dollars.
How's that sound?
Come on.
Here.
Good luck.
Fighters, centre of the ring.
Okay, your
trunks are good here.
Your trunks are good here.
I already explained to you
the rules earlier.
Protect yourself at all times.
If I say "stop" while
you're fighting, stop!
Do you have any questions?
You have any questions?
Touch gloves.
Go back to your corners.
Start!
One! Two! Three!
Four! Five!
Get up! Get up!
Six! Seven!
Eight! Nine! Ten!
- Look at you.
- Stop.
Christy. Larry Carrier.
You did great.
Well done.
- Thank you, sir.
- You earned that.
That was fun.
Hey, let me talk to you
about something real quick.
I loved what I saw
out there tonight.
I got a trainer who
wants to meet you.
His name's Jim Martin.
He's an excellent trainer.
Trains my son,
as a matter of fact.
Why don't you come up
next week
for a couple of days
and meet him?
Have a look around my gym,
work out with him some.
See if you like it.
If you do,
I want to promote you.
Get you more fights.
Yeah, okay, sure.
Maybe you want to bring
your father up with you.
Um, my dad can't
take time off work.
Okay, well, bring
your mom then.
Just your mom. Jim's a...
He's a family guy.
You understand me?
Yes, sir.
He's excited to meet you,
Christy.
Let's see if we can't
make a boxer out of you.
Can I help you?
I'm looking for Jim Martin.
That's him, over by the ring.
Excuse me.
Are you Jim Martin?
I'm Christy Salters.
Mr. Carrier told me
you'd be expecting me.
I'm here to train with you.
Hands up!
- Sir!
- What?
I'm working.
Tony's trying to concentrate.
What do you want?
Hey, where you going, hmm?
-  Christy! You made it!
- He doesn't want to train me.
- He's an asshole.
- Christy!
- Jim! Hey Jim!
- Yep?
Get down here.
Keep it up, fellas.
Jim, this is, ah,
Christy Salters.
Told you she was
coming in today.
Oh, yeah. Hi, Christy.
Pleased to meet you.
Hey, Jim Martin.
- I'm Joyce. I'm Christy's mum.
- Pleasure.
Larry paid for
the hotel already.
You said you were
gonna give it a try.
I said I'd come and
check it out. I checked it out.
The guy's a dick.
I wanna go home.
I just think if Larry's offering
you a place to stay, rent-free
and a job, and a trainer,
that's a real opportunity.
And now you're just
being ungrateful.
He don't wanna train me.
You saw it. It was embarrassing.
Well, fine.
We'll go home.
Didn't come all the way
down here
thinking you were going to
quit so easy is all.
And just 'cause a man said
something mean to you,
well that's how training works.
It's tough. It is supposed
to toughen you up.
Hmm...
I honestly thought you
was tough already.
I want to see
how you move.
Use your jab. Show me
some of your combinations.
Nothing too fancy.
Walt, go easy on her.
Let's see what you got.
Get her out of here.
Bust her up. Break a rib
if you have to.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to.
-  Jesus Christ.
- I'm sorry.
Huh.
Alright, Christy,
this is you.
Utilities are all paid for.
Telephone's connected
to the office,
so any calls that
come through for you,
they'll just patch them over.
After hours,
calls come directly to you.
If anyone calls the office,
then just take a
message for Polly.
Or, you could have Polly have
them all go to the machine,
but then that means that
nobody can call you at night.
I'm guessing you
don't want that.
You can figure
it out with Polly.
Anything else,
give me a call.
You only got twelve days
before this next fight,
so make 'em count.
No problem.
Alright.
Get over here.
Push off the back foot,
step, snap the punch.
Elbows in!
What's your hand doing?
Get your hands up
or you're gonna get yourself
knocked on your ass.
What'd ya eat?
A burger.
Yeah, I come for the steaks.
The steaks are good.
You wanna sit?
Sure.
-  Well, hey Jim.
-  Hey.
Just the usual?
- Appreciate it.
- Okay.
Are you gonna have
the pie again, hon?
- Yes please, ma'am.
- She'll just have coffee.
I don't want coffee.
Well, I don't want to
train a fat fighter.
Just the check, please.
You work harder than
most of the men I train.
I'm training my ass off.
Larry's a smart guy.
He seems to think
there's something to this lady
boxing business, I don't know.
We'll see.
Maybe he's right.
Maybe I'm gonna make you the
best woman fighter in the world.
How you feeling?
Good, I think.
Just jab, jab, jab.
Turn her like a top.
I'm gonna go watch 'em
wrap Whitcomb's hands.
You look cute.
You look good in there.
Just keep snapping
those jabs, yeah?
Move your head.
Jab, jab, jab.
Go back.
Yeah!
Five! Six!
Seven! Eight!
Nine! Ten!
Yeah! Yeah!
Well done!
Yeah! Okay!
Can you fucking
believe this?
I mean, it felt so great.
I don't even know
how to describe it,
but it was fucking amazing.
I mean, this other girl,
she was tough,
but she was slow so I kept
slipping all of her punches
and all my jabs were landing.
It was just...
I think I've found my thing.
I bet most people
go their entire lives
and they don't even know
what their thing is.
Here, take this.
Alright. Let's go.
Rosie, you still there?
So, boxing's
your thing?
Yeah, maybe.
I mean, I don't know.
I'm really fucking good at it.
But it's not a career,
is it?
I've got another
fight in six weeks.
I was thinking maybe you might
want to come to it.
Yeah, maybe.
I don't know.
Larry's also got me a job at the
supply store next to the gym.
For a little extra cash--
Christy, I wanted to do
this face to face, I did.
But also, I just need to
come out and say it.
I guess I thought this
could work, long distance,
but... I met someone.
I met a guy.
You'd actually like him,
I think. I don't know.
I feel really bad
about this--
One! Two! Three!
Four! Five! Six! Seven!
Eight! Nine! Ten!
Yeah! Yeah!
That's Christy!
Yeah!
- Oh!
- Yeah!
Yeah!
Whoo!
Oh!
Oh, man.
- There it is. It's over there.
You play angry.
That is what my
basketball coach told me.
I am too aggressive.
That's why I like boxing.
Well, boxing is only about
five percent aggression.
The rest of it is
strategy and control.
It's chess.
You can't play chess angry,
can you?
You're setting up moves.
I mean, you're slipping,
you're feigning.
You think I'm going
over here,
but I'm actually
going over here.
You're playing
a character.
You're the little
pretty pink character.
You should grow
your hair long.
It'd look better longer.
It gets in my face.
You'd look prettier
with longer hair.
Looks butch like that.
Nobody wants to see
a butch girl fight.
You know that.
Don't you?
I spoke to Joyce.
She said you had to
leave West Virginia.
She told me about Rosie.
When did you talk
to my mom?
Why don't
you have a boyfriend?
Don't think you can get a man?
I just...
I just wanna put
all my energy into boxing.
Yeah.
I see that.
I might rag on you
sometimes,
but it's only because I
want you to work hard.
I want you to work hard because
I think you've got something.
I'm not sure what that
something is,
but it's something.
I believe that.
Your shot.
Hello.
Hey there,
it's Jim.
What you doing?
Um...
Nothing.
- Just sitting.
- You wanna come over?
Hey.
We should
get to the gym.
Johnny Salters speaking.
Hey Dad.
Hey, sweet pea.
How are you?
I'm alright.
Are you okay, honey?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I just miss you.
I think I want to
come home.
Come here.
Hey.
I said I'd try it out
for six months.
I did that.
I need to start thinking about
what I'm actually going
to do with my life.
Boxing.
Boxing's what you're gonna do.
- You're doing it.
- I can't make a living doing it.
Larry can't find women
to fight me.
I've trained a lot of guys,
and...
I never had one
that I really thought
had what it takes
to go all the way.
You're lucky if you get one
of those your whole life.
That's what I see in you.
I'm serious when I say
I can make you the greatest
female fighter in the world.
Compared to who?
Nobody's doing it.
Nobody's getting paid
to do it.
That's gonna change.
Lenny Del Percio in Florida
wants to promote you.
He's got an apartment
for us in Daytona,
and he can get us fights.
And when the time is right,
I'll make the call to Don King.
Don just moved back to Miami,
and when you're ready
I'll make the call.
But you gotta do the work.
You gotta want it.
Now, if you wanna
stay here in West Virginia
I can't stop you.
But, I don't think you do.
I can see it
in your eyes.
And I got this real nice
situation set up
just waiting for us
in Daytona.
Daytona Beach?
Daytona Beach.
Daytona Beach, baby!
Now Aaron Pryor
is a buddy of mine.
You know Aaron Pryor.
He's a fighter.
Yeah, he's a fighter.
Yeah, legend from Ohio.
Oh!
He introduced me
to Mike Buffer.
Oh!
You know who
Mike Buffer is?
No.
"Let's get ready
to rumble!"
Oh my goodness!
How far is the beach?
I can't do this.
It doesn't feel right.
This doesn't feel right.
Just treat her the
same as a man.
It's fine, Shortdog.
Go easy on him,
Christy. He's only small.
I'm kicking your ass next.
Back to your corner!
Yeah!
Keep moving your head.
Watch the jab, use your right.
You gotta fix that
face, Christy. Fix his face!
Get her. Fuck her!
Yeah!
That's it, champ!
Hello?
Hey, how are you doing?
Yeah, that'd be great.
I'd love to see you.
Where're you thinking?
How about two?
Great.
Can't wait to see you.
I've been winning.
A lot. Like every fight.
Thanks.
He knows a lot of
really good people.
So yeah.
Feels like something
really big could happen.
That's great.
What about you and him?
- Jim?
- Mm-hm.
It's fine.
I don't know.
- My momma loves him.
- Mm-hm.
Every time she calls,
she just wants to talk
to him and not me.
What's the sex like?
I don't know, you tell me.
How would I know?
Well, how's your boyfriend?
Yeah, that didn't work out.
- He was a dick.
- Thought you liked dicks.
I need to talk to you.
Jim, this is Rosie.
Outside.
What are you--
Hey, don't fucking
grab at me!
What are you doing sneaking
around behind my back?
- I'm not sneaking around!
- What's she doing here?
She's in town
to see her grandma.
We were just
having a drink.
How do you think
that makes me look,
you sitting in a bar
with a damn lesbian?
I don't know.
Who the fuck cares?
I called your dad.
What'd you say?
I told him I was worried
you might be gay.
Jim, why would you say that?
I'm in the damn dark here.
You're breaking his heart.
You're gonna lose
your family.
Is that what you want?
You're gonna lose
your trainer...
Jim, we were just
having a drink.
...who's turning you
into a great fighter.
I'm the only one
who believes in you.
I mean, I'm the guy who can pick
up the phone to Don King,
right when you're
about to take off,
and you're gonna go do this,
for what?
So you can be a damn dyke
boxer nobody wants to train?
Jim, I'm not...
See, that in there
is your past.
Not your future.
Your future is with me.
You understand?
We're right there.
Why can't you see that?
We're... in this together.
We're a team.
You want to lose that, huh?
You want to lose your family,
your trainer, your career,
all of it?
Or do you want to marry me?
Well, come on,
I'm on one knee, dammit.
Christy Salters,
will you marry me?
Fuck, just get up already.
- Okay, just get up!
- Okay? Yes?
- Yes, just get up.
- Yes?
Yes! Get up, Jim.
- Yes, alright.
- Alright!
- Okay! Whoo!
- Alright.
Jim and Christy Martin.
Hey Jim, it's Johnny.
Hey, Johnny,
how you doing?
Good. Is Christy there?
Oh, no, you just
missed her.
She went out for a run.
But I will tell her
you called.
And I'm in a little bit
of a rush, too.
-  Oh.
- Yeah.
But will you send
my love to Joyce?
- Yeah, will do.
- You take care now.
-  Who was that?
- No one.
What if I did a couple of shifts
a week down at the drugstore?
They're looking for people.
You wanna box, or you
wanna work at a drugstore?
I wanna be able to pay
the damn phone bill.
We need to earn some money.
Or maybe I just
go back to Itmann.
If you leave me, I'll kill you.
You just need to be seen
by the right people.
You just keep training
and be ready when
the opportunity comes.
I am ready.
I don't know what else
I'm supposed to do.
I mean, I'm training my ass off,
I'm winning my fights.
Well keep doing that.
One of us has gotta get a job.
I can't keep asking my
dad to send us money.
I mean, why don't you
just get a job?
I have a job.
I'm your trainer.
Well, it's not paying
the damn bills.
I mean, what kind of man has
a job that can't pay the bills?
I'm not getting
enough fights and...
And I'm not getting paid
enough when I do get 'em
and I just want to make sure
that if we're gonna--
I told you what you could do
to make some more money,
didn't I?
And you didn't want to do it,
because you're too good for it
and that's fine.
But if you don't want to do it
how about you stop bitching to
me about the damn phone bill!
Douglas?
Jim, and Christy.
You to the corner!
Five! Six! Seven!
Eight! Nine! Ten!
Yeah!
Man, she didn't
stand a fucking chance.
Bam!
She went down.
You did great.
Right, here.
Christy! I want you to meet
an old friend of mine.
Jessie Robinson.
Christy. It's a pleasure
to meet you.
I mean, that was
one hell of a show.
Hey.
Jim Martin.
- Nice to meet you.
- Yeah, likewise.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
We gotta get her
out of here.
She needs to meet Don.
Well, yeah...
Want to pop outside
and have a chat?
Shit.
Fuck, why didn't
you check the oil?
Why didn't you check the oil?
'Cause it's your job,
you're a man,
and men are supposed to
check the goddamn oil.
- I gotta pull over.
- No, we can't be late.
Do you wanna blow
a head gasket?
I don't give a fuck
what we blow
as long as it's not
this goddamn meeting!
We're gonna go meet Don King!
We're gonna go meet
Don fuckin' King!
Fuck!
Ho!
- Here he is!
- Hey, Don.
Alright, alright!
Good to see you, Don.
- You know Jim Martin.
- Nope.
- I thought you two met.
- Yeah, we met back in Detroit.
- Nope.
There were a lot of
people around--
Nope. I don't forget people.
So, you're the trainer
and the husband?
- Yes, sir.
- I like that.
And you must be the lady I've
been hearing so much about.
Christy.
How old are you?
I'm twenty-four, sir.
You're pretty.
And you're really a fighter?
Yes, sir. It's an honor
to meet you, Mr. King.
Well, tell me about yourself.
Jessie here says that
you fight in all pink.
That's good. I like pink.
Well I'm from West Virginia.
What's that got to do
with pink?
Nothing, sir. I'm just
telling you about myself.
Pink was my idea.
West Virginia.
Coal-mining country.
Yes, sir. My daddy and my
brother work the mines.
So why in the hell are
you fighting Christy?
What's a pretty girl
like you doing
getting punched in the face
for a living?
I'm good at it, sir.
And I figured you could help me
with the making a living bit.
Okay, I like you.
I wanna see what you got.
I have never had a
lady fighter in my office.
- Jessie says you have a tape.
- Yes, sir.
Bonnie!
Put Christy's tape
in the machine.
Is it on
the right channel?
I think so.
I can hear it
spinning in there.
Is it connected
to the TV?
Damn. Oh well,
just leave it there.
- I'll look at it later.
- No!
Wait, no. Ah...
Ooh!
Show him your left hook, baby.
Left hook.
Okay, Christy, okay.
Okay, Christy.
You look good.
A coal miner's daughter
who fights in pink trunks
and sleeps with her
corner man.
I love it.
Fuck it.
Sign her up.
Let's do it.
Bonnie, have Dana
draw up a contract.
Five six-round fights
at five thousand a fight.
Honey, I'm gonna throw
you in there.
Sink or swim.
But what I need
from you - fight good,
and make sure everybody's
saying your name.
You hear me?
Yes, sir.
- Thank you, Mr. King.
- Yeah.
Thank you, Don.
We'll take that contract,
show it to our lawyer
and get it right back to you.
- Your name is Jim.
- Yes, sir.
How much did she
make on her last fight?
Four hundred dollars.
That contract don't
leave this office.
You sign it here,
or you don't sign it at all.
Only in America, baby.
Only in America.
Oh boy,
ladies and gentlemen,
have I got a treat for you.
I want to introduce to you
the first lady of boxing.
A new and dynamic and
beautiful boxing sensation.
The Coal Miner's Daughter -
Christy Martin!
Y'all give it up now.
Give it up everybody.
Y'all keep your hands
going now.
Come on up here, baby.
- Thank you, Mr. King.
- Yes.
I want to thank you
for this opportunity
and say what an honor it is
to be fighting on a
Mike Tyson undercard.
I can hardly believe it.
And to be the first woman fight
on pay-per-view -
I don't think I could have ever
dreamed I'd be here.
But here I am.
And can I just say,
I don't expect people
to be tuning in
because I'm the first
woman or whatever.
Everyone should watch because
I'm the best and I can fight.
And I'm going to prove that
Saturday night
when I stop Deirdre Gogarty
in such spectacular fashion
that every motherfucker
in that arena
is going to be
talking about it.
So get ready,
honey,
'cause Christy Martin's going
to knock you the fuck out.
Christy Martin,
everybody!
Stay still.
Ho! There she is!
The Coal Miner's Daughter.
The whole coal mining family.
You must be the coal miner.
Yeah, that's right.
How you feeling, baby?
- I feel okay.
- I hope so.
Make this a good fight.
Please don't let me down.
Make this a real good fight.
I'm sticking my dick out
on this one.
I will.
Thank you, Mr. King.
Okay.
Stay still.
- Hey, be still.
- I'm trying.
Oh! It's freezing.
I thought the desert
was supposed to be hot.
I didn't bring a coat with me.
Hey, let's go
shopping tomorrow.
I can't think about that
right now, Mama.
Can't think about what
right now?
Joyce?
Let her be.
What am I doing?
I'm talking to my daughter.
I never see her anymore.
Goddammit!
Okay, everybody out.
Let's go get our seats, huh?
Let's go.
I'm so fucking nervous.
I can't get my hands
to stop shaking.
Hey, you're okay.
You're fine.
You just treat it
like any other fight.
I can't.
This is huge.
Just do what you do, baby.
You've done the work.
Bring that action.
Okay?
You're a star.
You bring that action.
Introducing to you first,
on my left - fighting out
of the blue corner -
joining us from Dublin, Ireland,
at 130 pounds with a record
of ten wins and three losses,
two draws, nine wins
coming by way of knockout
introducing the hard-hitting
Deidre Gogarty!
And her opponent -
fighting out of the red corner -
she weighed in at the
lightweight limit
of 135 pounds even,
coming to you by way of
Mullens, West Virginia
with a record of 34 wins,
two losses and two draws,
she has 25 wins
by way of knockout -
introducing The Coal Miner's
Daughter - Christy Martin!
-  Come on!
-  Come on, Christy!
Come on!
Come on, sweet pea!
Ten seconds.
Whoo!
Four! Five!
Six! Seven! Eight!
Whoo!
Step.
Yeah!
Keep going!
Come on!
Break!
Break, break!
You're doing good,
but you gotta use that jab more.
She keeps going backwards.
Well, use that jab. Throw
that right hand behind it.
How's that nose?
I'm fine, Doc.
I'm really fine.
That's it!
After six rounds of boxing
we go to the judges' scorecards
where we have a
unanimous decision.
The judges scored the bout
60-54,
59-54 and 60-53,
all three in favor
of the winner,
The Coal Miner's Daughter -
Christy Martin!
The Coal Miner's
Daughter -
Christy Martin!
Maybe
after this, Christy,
we could get you
in your kitchen
cooking breakfast or
something like that.
Boxer by night, housewife by
day - sort of thing, you know.
But don't worry,
it'll be fun and playful.
Oh, we get it.
Yeah, we've done a bunch
of this stuff.
She just did Jay Leno and
Good Morning America.
Oh, that's great.
So, Christy,
they are calling your fight
with Deirdre Gogarty,
"the most lucrative bloody
nose in boxing history".
You're the first woman boxer
to ever appear on the cover
of Sports Illustrated.
You have been called
the fighter that's
put women's boxing on the map.
And yet you are on
record saying
that you're not really
interested
in being a champion
for women in sport?
I don't see that
as part of my job.
I'm not here to give some kind
of leg up to other women.
I'm here for one thing,
and that's Christy Martin.
I want to be recognized
as a great fighter, period.
Christy's a regular wife, actually.
She's very ladylike herself.
I mean, she cooks,
she cleans, all that,
but she ain't no feminist.
I'm just a regular wife
who happens to knock
people out for a living.
Good.
Christy!
Meet your new
cut man, Miguel.
I hear you're the best.
I'm not so bad.
Well, I got a nose that
loves to bleed.
I could have stopped it
in the Gogarty fight.
Good thing you weren't
in my corner, then.
That nose is making me
a lot of money.
That bitch
is fighting dirty.
She's using her
fucking head.
You don't put up with that.
You put her on her ass.
Get back.
Back to your corner.
I just wanna say Lisa Holewyne,
you're looking real nice.
This is the first time
I've seen you in a nice dress
looking like a woman.
But when I'm done with you,
you're gonna be so ugly
that not even your girlfriend's
gonna recognize you.
Okay ladies,
we went over the rules
in the dressing rooms.
I want you to protect
yourself at all times
and keep the fight clean
at all times.
Touch gloves.
Good luck.
Good luck getting
knocked the fuck out.
There it is!
Stick and move!
The winner, the Coal Miner's
Daughter - Christy Martin!
Hi Mom, hi Dad,
I love you!
Well, if you ask me
I'm the best thing that's ever
happened to women's boxing.
I've done more for the sport
than anyone else, and frankly,
I'm not getting
paid enough for it.
So, you'd like to see
women boxers
get paid more for their efforts?
Well, I don't know about other
women, but I definitely should.
Don King, if you're watching
I think pretty little Christy
here wants a raise.
And, we're out.
Love your work, Christy!
-  Hey.
-  Hi.
Nope, no, it has to be
five or five-thirty.
-  Hey, Big Jeff.
- Hey, champ.
Yeah, that works.
What are you doing?
Where's Shortdog?
I sent him home.
I'm gonna spar with you today.
Are you still pissed at me
about this morning?
No.
Get changed.
I'm sorry, what--
He's our neighbor.
What am I supposed to do?
He was being polite,
I was being polite back.
Get ready.
Have you heard
from Don yet?
Yeah, I'll handle it.
I know you're handling it,
I just want to know
if you heard anything.
I'm in the deep freeze
over here.
I just want to know when this
contract's gonna get done.
- Yeah I'll get it done.
- When?
If you screwed us by making me
say that dumb shit on TV
about wanting more money.
Yeah, what?
I wanna fight.
I need a contract.
Alright, come on.
When was the last time
you called him?
Keep your hands up.
- Have you even tried him?
- Keep your hands up.
You gotta call his office
every few hours
just to check in--
I told you to keep
your hands up.
- What happened?
- Oh, she...
She just ran right
into my punch.
- She wasn't concentrating.
- Let me see.
Let me see.
Baby, you just
ran right into it.
You know you're not good
at moving your head.
You okay?
She's not that good
at moving her head.
We gotta work on that.
Alright.
Let's get you out of here.
Come on.
On June 28th, in the year
of Our Lord 1997,
Tyson's gonna fight Evander
Holyfield at the MGM Grand.
I'm putting you on the card
against Andrea DeShong.
Thank you, DK.
I promise it'll be a good fight.
I mean,
I'll mess her up.
That dyke bitch is crazy.
She fucking hates me
for some reason.
Ha!
For some reason!
I like you, Christy.
You got some real personality.
But if I ever hear you
talking smack about me
to the press again.
Bitching about your
purses being too small
or whatever else -
there ain't gonna be
no more fights.
Do you hear me?
Yes, sir.
Now, I know you gonna
beat DeShong, baby.
That's what you do.
You're the queen right now.
Ain't that right?
You think you what makes
the world turn.
But one day you
gonna wake up and realize
that it turns just fine
without you.
And sugar, that morning's
gonna come like--
It has been billed
the greatest fight
in women's boxing history.
Laila Ali, daughter of the
greatest fighter of all time.
Her record speaks for itself -
15 fights, 15 wins.
And Christy Martin,
the 14-year pro
who single-handedly
put her sport on the map,
with 45 victories, 2 defeats,
31 wins by way of knockout.
But does this veteran have
what it takes to beat a fighter
now considered the new face
of women's boxing?
I was the past, I'm the present,
and I'm the future.
You know,
I was thinking maybe
we could bring on
someone else
to co-train with you
on this one?
Just for a couple of weeks.
Just a co-trainer.
Not a trainer.
You're still my trainer.
I just want someone who can help
take me to the next level.
You think I can't take you
to the next level?
It's not...
It's not that you're not
training me right.
My fault you're not at
the next level?
We just gotta figure out how
I'm gonna beat this girl.
She's younger and
bigger than me.
Do you want me
to call off the fight?
Do I tell 'em to keep
their money?
God...
- Do I tell 'em that?
- Jim.
Jim, I'm not trying to
undermine you.
Christy's not at
the right level.
She doesn't think she can
get to the next level.
I know I can beat her.
I just...
We were all talking yesterday.
We were all thinking that maybe
we could mix up my training
and make sure I'm ready.
We... we all?
Who the fuck is 'we all'?
Big Jeff and Miguel and me.
We were thinking--
So you're sneaking
behind my back at the gym?
You're talking to my guys
at my gym
about how you
should be training?
It's not your gym,
it's our gym!
You shit
your pants and blame me?
Come on,
take it easy.
Okay! Okay guys,
just take a break.
What's the matter with you?
We gotta fight different.
You can't slug Ali, you're not
gonna beat her that way.
You gotta fight her like
you fought Lisa Holewyne.
We gotta prep like
we prepped for that fight.
You need to spar with
someone better.
Shortdog ain't gonna
get you there.
I'll get Lisa in
to spar with you.
Lisa Holewyne isn't gonna want
anything to do with me.
We'll see about that.
Take five, guys.
See you later, Jeff.
I'm out of here.
Yo, champ. Come in.
What's up?
Have a seat.
How you feeling?
I'm good.
You're training hard.
I've never seen you
train this hard.
Well Laila's...
Laila's no joke.
And how's everything else?
You okay?
Yeah.
I'm just checking in.
That's all.
If you ever need anything...
I'm here.
Anything.
Yeah, I know.
Thanks.
Christy,
will show you around.
Why don't you get warmed up
and we'll get to it?
I really didn't expect you
to come.
Yeah, well,
I actually need the money.
We don't all get purses
like yours.
We're paying you?
How much?
Not enough for you
to be an asshole.
Create angles.
Get out of there.
Hey, create angles.
You good?
Yeah, I'm good.
You're good?
Find it, please.
Call me back.
How do you think she's looking?
She's looking good.
She's a little chunky, but she
had to come up in weight
so it is what it is, I guess.
You know, Jim, I don't mean to
question her abilities,
but I'm worried
about this fight.
I'm bigger than Christy and
Laila's too big for me.
I bet you wish it was you
going up against Ali.
No. I don't think
I could beat her.
You're right, you couldn't.
Christy can.
She keeps her head right,
and her attitude.
So yeah. Now's probably the
time for you to leave.
When Big Jeff gets back,
he'll take care of whatever
we still owe you.
We really appreciate you
coming out.
You know when we
fought you beat me
because you fought smart.
You know it.
And to beat Laila, you're going
to have to fight smart.
I'm going to peek-a-boo
that bitch.
She's going to think
I'm over here,
but actually I'm over here.
She ain't gonna
know where I am.
Okay.
Well, thanks for
having me come in.
It wasn't my idea.
I wanted a new trainer.
I got you instead.
You know how easy you make it
for people to dislike you?
It's like all this
tough girl shit.
Bravado.
Maybe Jim tells you to do it,
I don't know.
Maybe it's all part of the show.
I don't know who's telling you
what, but you don't need it.
Whatever you say.
Do you remember
what you said to me
when I wished you
good luck before our fight?
Yeah. I remember.
You were fucking with me.
No. I was just
wishing you luck.
Sorry, ma'am.
Restroom's occupied.
Right on.
Here we go.
Laila Ali, 162.
Whenever you're ready.
Christy Martin, 159.
Yeah!
We should have made her
come down more.
I'm 143.
By the time she rehydrates,
she's gonna be 170.
You're nervous. You're always
nervous before fights.
Get off your legs.
I should be fighting
Lucia Rijker.
You know she
wants to fight me.
I mean,
that makes sense.
Rijker is small time.
You're big time.
Get off your feet.
Excuse me, ma'am.
I just want to let you know that
I'm rooting for you tomorrow.
I think you can beat her.
Stay focused.
Hey, this isn't right.
She shouldn't be making
Christy wait.
Well that's the coin toss.
It's bullshit.
Well, I don't know what
you want me to say.
You guys lost the toss.
Goddammit.
Ali! Ali! Ali!
It's all good.
Focus on my hands.
Ali! Ali! Ali! Ali!
Ali! Ali! Ali! Ali! Ali! Ali!
Get that up there.
Alright, Laila.
Come on, Christy.
Ladies, you both
received instructions
in the dressing room.
I told you what I
expected of both of you.
Don't make me have
no decision in the fighting.
Touch 'em up,
come out fighting. Let's go.
Let's go.
Come on,
get in there!
Come on, get in there!
Guard up!
Break up, break up, break up.
Why are you slugging?
Am I fighting crooked?
I'm dizzy.
No, you're alright.
Just keep your defense up.
Don't slug at her.
I'm dizzy.
I feel like I'm on a slant.
Don't slug at her.
Enough of that.
- Let's go, let's go!
- Stay off the ropes!
Breathe in through the nose -
out through the mouth.
I'm still dizzy.
I can't get my balance back.
Hey. You're alright.
You're alright.
Just give me one more round.
Get your composure back.
Seconds up!
Break, break.
Jim, she's not good.
You should throw in the towel.
Get in close, Shortdog.
Get in close. Get out.
Move. Move.
You're short, Shortdog.
Use it. Stay in close.
Who's the
fucking trainer here?
You keep running
your damn mouth.
Alright.
Dig in.
Jim. I'm done.
I'm not feeling great.
Two more rounds.
I'm not feeling it today.
Two more rounds
on the heavy bag.
Why?
- I don't have a fight.
- I'm working on that.
How?
Well, I spoke to Bob Arum
and he said a Lucia Rijker
fight is looking good.
When?
Why didn't you tell me?
I don't have the details.
He's getting into it.
Just stay ready.
Have you
heard from Bob?
Bob who?
Bob Arum.
Do you know anything more
about the Rijker fight?
Why is Deana
calling you again?
Because I need a haircut.
She called you yesterday.
Yeah, well,
I missed her call yesterday.
How many calls does it take
to organize a haircut?
It only takes one,
but you actually have to talk
to the person
to make the appointment.
It's like every time
I pick up your phone,
there's another call
from her.
Okay, so why the fuck
are you looking
at my phone all the time?
Stop looking at my phone!
I have to look at your phone. I
need to know what you're doing.
How else am I going to know
what you're doing?
I'm getting a damn haircut.
Give me my phone back.
Why are you getting a haircut?
Because that's what
people do.
They get fucking haircuts.
You just had one.
I had one two months ago.
Then it fuckin' grew.
Maybe you'd understand
if you had any hair to cut.
Ha, ha.
It's the Salters!
Heya Jim,
where's the birthday girl at?
Hi, come on.
Good to see you.
-  Hey Jim.
- Come on in.
Well, Bob thinks
it's a good idea.
Tie in the fight with the home
video release of the movie -
a marketing tie in.
Mm, yeah, Rijker was
involved in that film.
Yeah.
Get Hillary Swank on board.
-  Huh.
-  Yeah.
-  Hilary Swank?
-  No way.
-  Yeah.
That's awesome, boss.
Hi.
Mom, I need to talk to you
about something.
Well, yeah.
Shoot.
Can I talk to you in private?
Will you go out front with me?
Things aren't right.
He knows everything I do
or say inside the house.
He must have the
whole house set up
with hidden cameras
or something.
And he's angry at me
all the time.
What's he angry about?
Everything.
And there's other stuff too,
Mom.
He's making videotapes of us
doing stuff.
He's scaring me.
I don't know what
I'm supposed to do.
I don't want to be here.
I don't want him
to train me anymore.
I got this...
This fight with Lucia Rijker
coming up.
It's supposed to be
a real payday.
And I'm gonna
need that money.
Because I gotta
get out of here,
and I don't know what
I'm doing, and I don't...
I don't even know how
I got in this situation, but...
I need help, Momma.
Oh...
Oh, Christy.
You sound crazy.
Jim told me you've been messing
around with some kind of drugs.
And I can't tell you
how to live your life,
but you need to
get your act together.
I'm not comfortable
having this conversation
behind Jim's back,
so I'm gonna
go back in there
and you pull yourself together
before we do the cake.
I drove a long way
to be here for this.
I know, Momma.
♪ You are my sunshine
♪ My only sunshine
♪ You make me happy
When skies are gray ♪
♪ You'll never know, dear
How much I love you ♪
♪ Please don't take
my sunshine away... ♪
Oh yeah,
come over here.
Come over here
with that big dick.
♪ As I lay sleeping
♪ I dreamed I held you
in my arms ♪
♪ When I awoke, dear
I was mistaken ♪
♪ And I held my head
and cried... ♪
Hey champ, how you doing?
Yeah, I'm good.
Are you sure?
What do you need
to tell me?
Jeff?
Honey, you are like
family to me.
And you know I don't like
getting involved
in other people's
business but...
I am worried
about you.
I've heard some stuff.
What stuff?
Jeff, what stuff?
Jim has been skimming
money off of your fights.
He's been hiding the money
in a tin can in your backyard
and sending Marcel to go get it
while you're at the gym.
I think he's giving it to his
ex-wife or his kids.
I don't know what else
he would be doing with it.
And there's other things, too.
Videotapes.
Of you.
You know.
I think you need to be
very careful.
How do you
know about this?
The young guys at the gym...
They were saying some
things about it.
I was hoping you were going to
say that he's having an affair
and wants to leave me.
Sorry.
I didn't know what to do.
I gotta keep this Rijker purse
away from him, somehow.
How do I do that?
I need that money.
Champ... that fight
ain't happening.
I don't know why he
keeps telling you it's on,
but it's not.
Ahh!
You piece of shit!
You motherfucker!
I bled for that money,
you piece of shit!
It's not yours!
Calm down!
You're embarrassing yourself.
I'm leaving you.
No, you are not.
You are not leaving me.
There is no Christy Martin
without me.
You'd think you'd be a
little bit more grateful.
Where you been?
I thought maybe I'd order
us some ribs for dinner.
What are you doing?
Hold up, Christy.
Hold on.
We gotta talk. Christy?
Look at me.
Unpack that bag.
Christy, look at me.
All the sacrifices
I've made for you.
Where are you going?
If you leave me, I'll kill you.
You do what you
have to do.
Glad you called.
I've been following
your career.
It's amazing what you've done.
Thanks.
Is everything okay at home?
You sounded kind of edgy
on the phone.
You're still with Jim, right?
I'm gonna leave him.
Really?
- Hmm.
- Yeah.
You know, I haven't talked
to anyone about this.
I don't really have
anyone I can talk to.
What's going on?
I don't know...
I don't know. I don't even know
where to start.
I mean, I should have
done this years ago.
What's going on?
Is that him?
Do you need to answer it?
What?
I see
the way you greeted her.
What do you think
you're doing?
I'm so close
I could touch you.
What's going on?
He's here. He's watching us.
What do you mean?
What's he gonna do?
He's not gonna do
anything to you.
But we should go.
- I booked a hotel.
- I'm coming with you.
Where you been?
I couldn't sleep.
What the fuck?
What is it?
- Jeff?
- You okay?
I just turned my phone
back on.
I've got like
a hundred messages.
Jim sent a picture of me
to everyone.
Yeah.
What's going on?
What's the picture of?
It's um...
You know...
It's dirty, it's not good.
He's telling everyone you're
leaving him for a woman.
He sent the picture to everyone.
My boxing contacts,
my family, everyone.
Is there anything
you need me to do?
No, I gotta go.
Let's pack up and
get out of here.
You can call him
from my place.
Tell him you'll organize a truck
to come and pick up your stuff.
And then I'll call my friend
Sharon, who's a lawyer--
I'm going back home.
What?
I have to go back there.
I need to go home.
Are you fucking crazy?
I'm not running away.
I'm not going into
hiding somewhere.
I spent half my life hiding.
That's my house.
That's my things.
That's my fucking gym.
I'm not gonna let him
push me out.
I don't get it.
I don't understand you.
I want you to do
something for me.
I want you to memorize
my phone number.
Can you do that for me?
We have to talk.
I'm gonna lie down.
My head's killing me.
I'm gonna take a nap
and then we can talk.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I just had a nap.
Is he there?
Can you talk?
He's in the living room.
What happened
when you got home?
Nothing. I just told him
I had to take a nap.
I need to talk with you.
I'm on the phone.
I'll talk to you when I'm done
talking to Rosie.
I gotta go, Rosie.
Jim, I'm sorry.
Go ahead, call your girlfriend.
Please don't let me die.
Nope, it's not working either.
Please...
Please help...
Please help me.
Uh...
Yeah, go ahead.
- What happened?
- Drive, please sir.
I don't wanna die.
I'm sorry, I'm...
I'm getting blood
all over your seat.
Just keep breathing.
Let's get her
hooked up.
Get me some
saline and some gauze.
You can get her hooked up
to the monitor.
And Brooke, if you
can get an IV for me.
Hon, I'm gonna cut
your shirt open, okay?
We gotta look at your wounds.
One in the left AC.
Pulse is good on this side.
Alright, she's
bleeding pretty good over here.
I need two units, O-neg.
Hi, my name's Nancy.
I'm an ER nurse.
Can you tell me your name?
Christy Martin.
Okay, Christy, we're going to
take good care of you, okay?
Can you tell me what
happened to you?
I was shot and stabbed
by my husband.
It's okay, honey.
You're safe now, okay?
You're going
to be okay.
Is there anybody
I can call for you?
- Rosie.
- Rosie?
Okay, do you know
Rosie's number?
681 - 735 - 0102.
681 735 0102?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
I'm gonna go call her and tell
her what's happening, okay?
You're gonna be okay.
We're gonna take good care
of you, okay?
Let's get her
prepped for the move
and let's stop this bleeding.
Please call Rosie.
She's okay.
Sweetheart.
She's in bad shape, but the
doctors say she'll be okay.
Oh, sweetheart.
Has she been awake?
She was awake
when I, when I got here.
She's been in and out.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Can I talk to you outside, please?
You need to leave.
It's not right that you're here.
Christy wants me here.
Christy doesn't
know what she wants.
You're the reason
this has happened.
I'm her mother,
and I want you to leave.
And I don't wanna talk
anymore about it.
Where's Rosie?
She left.
Where'd she go?
I don't know.
- Where's Jim?
- He's been arrested.
The police found him.
Hiding in your neighbor's
tool shed.
He's lucky they found him
before I did.
I'd have killed that
son-of-a-bitch.
You know,
it's all over the news.
And everyone is saying,
that you were gonna
leave Jim for that woman.
That woman's name is Rosie.
I know.
So I thought,
that you could say,
that you were with
the other Rosie.
You know, Rosie Graham.
And that way people
would understand
that she's just a friend--
Mom.
What are you doing?
You're fucking kidding me?
You might as well have
pulled the trigger yourself.
I wish I could have been
the daughter you
wanted me to be.
I tried my whole life.
I tried so fucking hard
for you.
And look where I am, Momma.
Look where I am.
The doctor wants
you walking, Christy.
You've got your walker
right here.
I don't need that.
You don't go anywhere
without your walker.
Doctor's orders.
Lisa fucking Holewyne?
What the hell
are you doing here?
I hope it's alright
I just showed up.
I just wanted to see
if you were okay.
Thanks.
So who's Rosie?
You sure as hell didn't creep
quietly out of the closet.
Yeah...
You peek-a-boo'd this bitch.
Man...
People are gonna
tear me apart.
I spent half my career
trash-talking women I fought.
Calling them dykes
or whatever.
- Oh, really?
- Mm-hm.
Wow.
People are gonna
laugh in my face.
Maybe they will.
You deserve it.
Yeah.
But maybe they won't.
Maybe you've just learned to
expect the worst from people.
I want to fight again.
Really?
Yeah.
You know no one will hold it
against you if you don't.
Right?
You kicked every ass
there was to kick.
I want it back.
I want the ring back.
In there, I'm calm.
In there, it's quiet. Just
everything goes quiet, you know?
Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
There's rules and
there's boundaries.
Everywhere else is chaos,
but in there it's quiet.
And it's mine.
And I want it without him.
Well...
Good luck.
Thank you.
Okay, let's get you up.
Put that thing away.
- Come on, old lady.
- I ain't doing that.
Get you boxing ready.
- Let's go, granny.
- I ain't using that.
- Not using this?
- Uh-uh.
- I think it's required.
- It ain't.
No? I'll take it then.
Let's go.
It's nice.
It's good for dips.
Get a good workout in.
Keep up.
Psst! Yo.
Hey fellas, hold up.
I'm sorry.
I don't know, Christy.
Let me remind you, you got shot
and stabbed two weeks ago.
Yeah, so?
Yeah, so I don't know
that you should be training yet.
You need to get better first.
This is me getting better.
I want a fight.
I want you to train me.
Can you get me a fight?
Come on, Papi.
Get me a fight.
Jeff?
Alright, champ.
You've got it.
We'll get you a fight.
Fuck yeah!
I go to a restaurant
and I realize I don't know
what to order.
I don't know what to cook
for myself at home.
I don't know what
clothes I want to wear,
or what I want to
watch on television.
I have no idea
who I actually am.
Every aspect of my life has
been controlled by this man.
Every decision.
Everyone I talk to.
I don't know who
I can trust anymore.
Not even my own family.
I don't have many regrets
in my life.
But I regret not accepting help
when it was offered.
And I wish I would have
walked out
the first time
you promised to kill me.
Maybe I thought
you were joking.
But I know now that whatever
it was you intended,
a good man
doesn't say that shit.
But you said it.
You said it over and over again.
And then you came good
on that promise.
But guess what, motherfucker?
You didn't kill me.
Your Honor, I'm going
to object at this time.
This is confrontational.
Are you fucking
kidding me?
- I'm confrontational?
-  Sustained.
Miss Salters, I need you to just
read your statement, please.
You stabbed me.
Look at me!
Look at me, Jim.
You stabbed me.
You shot me.
You left me for dead
on the bedroom floor.
But like most else -
you came up short.
You came up short, didn't you,
you fucking piece of shit.
-  Objection.
-  Miss Salters.
It's alright.
I'm done.
Knock her out, champ.
"
by MONO playing]
" continues]